# RELAND BOYLE

# **Software Engineer**

+1 (631) 806-0019 • reland.boyle@gmail.com • New York, NY • linkedin.com/in/relandboyle • github.com/relandboyle

#### SUMMARY

Software engineer and generalist with 15+ years of varied professional experience across product development, mechanical design, project management, customer success, and full stack software development. Working in three mainstream programming languages and four frameworks. Known for rapidly becoming a subject matter expert, mentor, and trusted source of information.

#### **SKILLS**

JavaScript • TypeScript • Java • Dart • Angular • React • Spring • Flutter • D3 • RxJS • Node • Express • Docker • Kubernetes • OpenShift • PostgreSQL • MongoDB • Firebase • Material UI • Angular Material • Flutter Material • CSS/Sass/Less • Electron • AWS • Linode • Linux • OAuth • Auth0 • Grafana • Prometheus • GitHub • BitBucket •

# **Work Experience**

## Citigroup - Senior Software Engineer, Frontend

May 2022 - Present

- Developed 20+ REST endpoints and Java/Spring microservices to bring payment applications into compliance with ISO 20022
- Built an Angular web tool featuring interactive D3 force-directed graphs with physics simulation displaying microservice topology
- Devised an original hiring assessment system for React and Angular developers, providing work simulations to test 1000+ candidates annually, ensuring good hires and significantly increasing dev efficiency and code quality at the organization level
- Transformed 30+ developers into Full Stack Engineers as an FSTEP program SME in TypeScript/Angular and Java/Spring Boot

### DataCaliper - NetSuite Developer

November 2021 - March 2022

- Integrated SuiteScript 2.0 programs within SuiteCloud Developer Framework to customize NetSuite instances for multiple clients
- Produced Advanced PDF Templates, Workflows, and Formula Fields to reduce wait times and cognitive load by up to 60%
- Typically responded to client requests within 24 hours with effective, creative solutions and delivered within 5 business days

# Rich Brilliant Willing - Assistant Director of Operations

January 2016 - August 2021

- Optimized processes across departments, automated repetitive tasks and implemented integrations between Oracle NetSuite ERP/CRM and 4 secondary platforms, working with tech such as NetSuite Workflows and SuiteScript Developer Framework
- Achieved 100% product compliance with relevant consumer product safety standards and internal performance standards
- Founded and managed RBW's Customer Success Team, hired CSR's, established metrics and service level agreements, reduced post-sale support cases from 15% to 5% of all sales while mentoring team members and authoring internal tech wiki
- Routinely directed \$1M+ custom lighting projects through ideation, design, compliance, manufacturing, delivery, and installation

# **Recent Projects**

## **Drone Tools React**, **Drone Tools Angular**

April 2022 - November 2022

- Developed a single-page React/TypeScript application to calculate multirotor aircraft propeller tip speed relative to local Mach 1
- Completely rebuilt the application using Angular 13, RxJS Observables and operators, Reactive Forms, and Angular Material
- Employed Netlify/AWS Lambda serverless functions to mask sensitive user data in HTTP calls from client to 3rd-party API
- Introduced SCSS style sheets to achieve a responsive, mobile-friendly design that renders gracefully on displays up to 4k

#### **Skills Grid**

January 2022 - February 2022

- Constructed a full-stack JavaScript CRUD application to assist over 500 recent boot camp graduates in their first tech job search
- Deployed a Node/Express server and a vanilla JS (ES21) client relying on DOM manipulation and a MongoDB Atlas instance
- Authored 7+ modular LESS style sheets to provide consistent styling and transitions while writing more maintainable CSS

#### **KR8S for Kubernetes**

September 2021 - November 2021

- Created a React/Electron single-page desktop dashboard application to visualize and monitor Kubernetes cluster health and
  performance metrics, providing developers with real-time insight into the impact of changes made to the deployed application
- Automated deployment of a React/Express test application via multiple Docker containers in a local Kubernetes cluster with preconfigured Prometheus servers feeding Grafana dashboards for a 60% reduction in environment setup time for new users

### **EDUCATION**

- Codesmith Residency for Software Engineers Syllabus
- Dassault Systemes Certified SolidWork <u>Certificate</u>
- Suffolk Aviation Academy Private Pilot

### August 2021 - November 2021 January 2020 - June 2020

September 1994 - June 1996

### **ACHIEVEMENTS**

- Career Support Engineer for Codesmith Alumni
- Tech Talks Sponsored by Single Sprout: <u>User Experience Best Practices</u>

February 2022 - Present

October 2021